recipechart.com 2017-12-01

# Privacy Policy - Food Recipes, Dinner Ideas, Healthy Recipe Tips

This Privacy Policy covers the use of this website, RecipeChart.com. RecipeChart.com and any and all of the entities that control, own, or are affiliated with RecipeCharts.com are referred to herein as “RecipeChart.com” “We”, “Us” or “Our”. RecipeChart.com will maintain your data in connection with the use of RecipeChart.com as described in this Privacy Policy.

Your privacy is important to Us. To demonstrate Our commitment to Our users’ privacy, We provide the following Privacy Policy to inform you of Our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personally-identifiable information collected from you during your use of the Sites.

This Privacy Policy is an integral part of the Sites and cannot, in any way, be separated from the Terms of Service or from the usage or transaction process. If you do not agree to Our Privacy Policy in whole, you must not use RecipeChart.com.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time for any reason. It is your responsibility to review this privacy policy from time to time to ensure you agree with it, if you don’t agree with it then do not use RecipeChart.com. We suggest that you consult the Sites regularly to check for any changes to this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or Our privacy practices, please contact Us at support@recipechart.com.

We collect information in the following circumstances: (i) registering for an account, (ii) participation in surveys, sweepstakes, contests, and promotions (“Surveys and Promotions”), (iii) contacting Us, and (iv) visiting and browsing Recipechart.com.

**Registration**

Information collected during the registration process may include, but is not limited to, your name, company name, company address, phone number, username, email address, date of birth, account password. We may also collect your IP address when you register and use a Site. From time to time in the future, We may offer additional features, services, and promotional opportunities that may require you to submit additional information to participate.

**Surveys and Promotions**

We also collect certain information about you and your web browsing sessions if you participate in Surveys and Promotions, which allows Us to coordinate the marketing support that allows Us to continue to share Our knowledge, insights, and opinions. Participation in Surveys and Promotions is optional. Should you choose to participate, the information We collect for Surveys and Promotions may include your name, phone number, address, e-mail address, IP address, the website that referred you to the applicable Site, and other data.

**Contacting Us**

You may also contact Us by filling out and submitting a form through a Site, or by submitting feedback when you are logged in to a Site, or by simply emailing us at support@Recipechart.com. When you contact Us through a Site, your full name, message, and email address are transmitted to Us. Any other information you choose to include in the form you submit would also be transferred to and stored on Our servers.

**Anonymous Information**

We also collect “Anonymous Information,” such as traffic statistics and general usage patterns regarding page views, dates and times you use a Sites, the website that referred you to the Site, and the method by which you accessed the Site, files accessed through the Site, responses sent to the browser, the length of data sent to the browser, and other data used in the communication between browser and Sites.

**Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your computer with information about your visit to a particular site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. Session ID cookies are erased when you close your browser and do not last beyond one visit to Our Sites. Session cookies help Us keep track of information such as what service or product you are searching for. A persistent cookie is a small file stored on your hard drive for an extended period of time. These cookies are used to remember items like your login information if you have elected to have it remembered on your computer, and are used to target you for our other Sites.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. If you reject the cookie, you may not be able to fully use all of the functionality of the Site. In particular, session ID cookies are required to store relevant information as a user moves from page to page. Persistent cookies enable Us to track and target the interests of Our users to enhance the experience on Our Sites.

## How We Use the Information We Collect

The information you provide that can be used to locate or identify you is referred to as “Personally Identifiable Information.” We use it to provide Our Services and to communicate with you regarding such Services. We may also use your Personally Identifiable Information to provide information you have requested or products you have purchased (e.g., membership dues, event tickets), to resolve disputes, collect fees, and troubleshoot problems. We also may use your Personally Identifiable Information: to respond to specific inquiries made by you; to prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, and enforce Our Terms of Use; and to customize, measure, and improve Our Services, content, and layout. In addition, We analyze and use your Personally Identifiable Information — and supplement it with other information We obtain — to notify you and target advertising to you regarding special offers, products, services, and information that We think may be of interest to you, and to measure the advertising effectiveness of advertisements on Our Sites.

We use your Anonymous Information for the purposes of system administration, providing certain site functionality and content, targeted advertising, site tracking, and collecting and reporting aggregate usage information. We may combine Anonymous Information with your Personally Identifiable information to notify you of special offers and target advertising and other content to you.

## Phishing

We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, your username, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. Identity theft and the practice currently known as “phishing” are of great concern to Us. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is Our top priority. For more information about phishing, you may want to visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website at <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/alertsphishingalrt.htm> .

## Opt-in Emails, Text Messages and Offers

You may elect to receive updates from Us about special offers, new services, and other noteworthy news items. However, you must opt-in to these emails and text messages, and you may always choose to decline to receive these email messages and text messages at any time. Please see Our Opt-out policy described below. We will never sell, rent or share your personal information, including your email or phone number with and third parties for marketing purposes without your express permission. We may share your personal information with Our service delivery providers for the purpose of delivering Our email and text messages to your or as required by law.

## Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to opt-out of emails and text messages to which they have previously opted-in. This does not apply to emails that relate to Site information, Terms of Service, or that are automatically generated by the system (registration confirmation emails). Users who no longer wish to receive Our promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by clicking on the Unsubscribe link provided in emails.

## Information Sharing

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, We will not share your Personally Identifiable Information with third parties.

We may share your Personal Data with third party service providers to: provide you with the Services that we offer you through Recipechart.com; to conduct quality assurance testing; to facilitate creation of accounts; to provide technical support; and/or to provide other services to Recipechart.com. These third party service providers are required not to use your Personal Data other than to provide the services requested by Recipechart.com.

## Posting

Any information voluntarily disclosed by users and posted on the Sites (on message boards, web logs, and/or in chat areas) may be viewed and used by others. Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, We do not sell, rent, trade or give away any of your personal information including your last name and your email address. HWe reserve the right to sell, rent, share or trade your User Submissions (as defined in the Terms of Service posted on the relevant Sites) including your first name and initial of last name to third parties. If you post personal information that is accessible to the public online, you do so at your own risk. Be aware that you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties as a result.

## Third Party Service Providers

We engage certain third parties to perform various functions and provide services to Us (for example, web hosting services and maintenance services). These third parties may have access to some of your Personally Identifiable Information, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services, and only pursuant to binding contractual obligations requiring such third parties to maintain the privacy and security of your Personally Identifiable Information.

## Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement

We may choose to disclose some or all of your Personally Identifiable Information to the government, law enforcement officials, or private parties if We, in Our sole discretion, believe it necessary or appropriate to comply with the law, to respond to legal complaints, to comply with legal process (including subpoenas), to protect the rights of Our company or a third party, to ensure the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical, or legally questionable activity. Although We make every effort to preserve your privacy, We may be required by law to disclose information you have provided in obtaining Our services. We may also disclose information against someone who poses a threat to Our interests (such as customer fraud) or whose activities could bring harm to others.

## Changes in Corporate Ownership

If any or all of Our assets are acquired by, or merged with, another entity We will share some or all of your Personally Identifiable Information with that entity.

## Accessing and Changing Your Information

You may always access and modify certain of your Personally Identifiable Information you provide through Our self-service e-commerce platform by visiting the “sign in” area at the home page. You may or may not be able to modify the Personally Identifiable Information you provide through other parts of the Sites.

## **Links to Other Sites**

Our Sites may contain links to other websites, in several places. You should pay particular attention to which website you are visiting when submitting any Personally Identifiable Information to these websites. This Privacy Policy addresses the use and disclosure of only that information that We collect from you through RecipeChart.com. Different rules may apply to information you submit to other websites, and We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these websites.

We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of data after you click on links to such outside websites.

## Our Policy Toward Children

Recipechart.com does not intentionally provide access and content toward persons under thirteen years of age. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided Us with personally identifiable information without their consent, he or she should contact Us at support@recipechart.com. If We become aware that a child under thirteen has provided Us with Personally Identifiable Information, We will remove such information from Our files.

## Notification of Changes

If We decide to change Our policies, We will add those changes to this Privacy Policy and anywhere we deem appropriate so you are always aware of what information We collect, how We use it, and under what circumstances, if any, We disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected.

If, however, We are going to use your Personally Identifiable Information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, We will notify you via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not We use their information in this different manner.

## Third-Party Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

Contact Information

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding Our Privacy Policy, please contact Us at:support@recipechart.com
